Under the all-powerful
Administrator's rule,
this world entered a long period of
peace and the people became apathetic.
Seventy years had passed since
Quinella became Administrator.
Then, one day, she realized
she'd undergone a change.
She used her control command
to examine her Fluctlight and
discovered it had reached its
capacity to retain her memories.
She refused to accept it, so she came
up with another monstrous solution.
Welcome, child.
Please, come closer.
Yes, ma 'am.
If I can overwrite her Fluctlight with a
copy of the thoughts and
memories from my own,
I will never lose them.
Close your eyes.
It was a diabolical ceremony.
A fusing of soul and memory, which
she called the Synthesis Ritual.
With it, she could seize control
of another human's Fluctlight.
Right.
And here was where Administrator, or
Quinella, made a critical mistake.
What do you mean?
It didn't occur to her
that during the process of
taking over the young girl
and deleting her old self,
there would be a split
second where two gods
with equal power existed at the same time.
Kirito, you are familiar with my
original version, are you not?
What is the main feature
of the cardinal system?
Oh, um, it's supposed to operate
automatically for long periods of time.
It doesn't need humans to run.
That is correct.
And to facilitate it,
the Cardinal System has two core programs,
a main process and a sub-process.
The main process performs
balance controls on the system.
While the sub-process runs
error checks on the main.
Precisely.
When she became administrator,
the preservation of order wasn't the only
thing Queeniella etched
onto her Fluctlight.
In the recesses of her soul, I still
functioned as the sub-process to her main.
And I was obligated to correct her errors.
For 70 long years, I
waited for my opportunity.
And finally, it had arrived!
oh
oh oh
oh oh...
I can't believe it will be my hands.
I'll see the shapes of the darkness.
A beginning of the hole was happening.
I'll be in trouble with my heart.
I will be in pain with my friends.
I will push through it in my heart.
I'm ready to go and get ready to go.
I'm calling the words to you.
I'm ready to go.
I'm going to see you on the call.
Chinese of my diamond.
I'm a dream of my dream.
Daddy, dutchi akate, mon
pa, gyo, Mito, ki-tende.
Itsu, time, hei, kyo, no, i-nori-ga,
kakumei-no, dutusha, kakakakya-kei!
It worked.
This little girl's Fluctlight is mine now.
System call.
Generate luminous element.
Lightning shape.
Discharge! What?
System call.
Generate luminous element.
System Call, Generate Umbra
Element, Ball Shape, Discharge!
System Call, Redefine Object, Sword Class!
System Call, Redefine Object, Rod Class!
System Call, Change, Field, Attribute!
No!
She made this area off-limits
for system commands!
I can't defeat her in this body!
System call!
Generate aerial elements! Dream shape!
There are only two locations in this world
which Administrator has no control over.
One is the other side
of the End Mountains.
The other is...
System call!
Generate Blizzard Gate 01!
The Great Library!
In an instant, this space was
completely isolated from the outside.
For the past 200 years, I've
been watching and plotting.
I waited for the perfect moment when I
could catch her off guard, then ambush her.
She knew what I was up to
and was constantly on guard,
so she created powerful and
loyal servants for protection.
Through the Synthesis Ritual,
this man will be reborn as a
warrior devoted only to me,
my Integrity Knight.
The first one she turned into
an Integrity Knight was an
exceptional swordsman who
hated the rule of the Church.
Seeking refuge from it,
he and his companions founded
a village in the outer regions.
The name of this knight
was Bercoli Synthesis 1.
One-on-one, Administrator
and I are equally matched.
At least we were.
Her knights are fast and powerful.
They made the prospect of
ambushing her impossible.
So, at the risk of being spotted,
I sought out my own allies.
I opened doorways far from the cathedral,
then cast sensory-sharing
spells upon birds and insects
and sent them out to lead
potential allies back here to me.
Look here.
Meet Charlotte.
She spotted you and Eugeo
in Rulid and has been
tagging along with you ever
since you left that place.
Sometimes, she did more
than just tag along.
She was the one guiding me when
we were running from that night.
Huh, sneaky.
So back when my Zophilias got chopped
up, was that you giving me the pep talk?
She's a shy one.
Of all my observation units,
Charlotte has been out searching
longer than the others.
At last, she can rest now.
Her mission's come to an end.
When I enlisted her, I froze the
natural degradation of her life.
That was over 200 years ago.
Thanks, Charlotte.
So for 200 years, you had critters like
her out in the world looking for help,
and you've been stuck
in here the whole time?
Indeed.
And as I sat here, observing
the world through their eyes,
a question kept repeating.
Why would the gods of the
outside abandon a world they
created to suffer under the
tyranny of Administrator,
a false god.
As I pondered this and
referred to the Cardinal
System's built-in database over and over,
I eventually arrived at a conclusion.
Wrath may be the god here,
but it doesn't want the people
to lead happy lives at all.
It wants the opposite.
This is a test.
Wrath created the underworld
so they can observe how
its people react to stress
perimeters put upon them.
Day by day, they increase.
Eventually,
all those stressors
will reach their limit,
and the final phase of
the test will be at hand.
Then what happens?
What these people fear the most, an
invasion from outside this realm.
The Dark Territory. Correct.
The World of Darkness
was created to subject
the Underworldians to the ultimate agony.
The monsters there have
Fluctlights just like humans.
The difference is, their prime
directive is to plunder and slaughter.
They're eager for the day when they
can breach the land of the Eums,
as they call you,
and wreak havoc.
That day is coming.
And Administrator, does
she know they're coming?
Yes, but she underestimates them.
She thinks she and her Integrity
Knights are strong enough to repel them.
She even had all four guardian dragons
slain, north, south, east, and west.
As allies, they would have been
valuable, but she could not control them.
Pity, she cannot win now, for the
forces of darkness are too many,
and her numbers are too few. Hang on.
If that's true, then why
bother taking her down?
Because it sounds like the fate of this
world sealed whether you do or don't.
You are correct.
No matter what I do,
the Dark Territory will invade the human
realm, and there is no stopping it.
So, like, once you stop Administrator,
your job here is done and
whatever else happens, happens.
You don't care, do you?
Perhaps I don't.
However...
Wrath engineered the
bloodshed that is to come.
I cannot accept a god who does that.
Once I learned the load test
was unavoidable, I decided.
The human realm and the dark territory
must be returned to nothingness.
Hold up. Decided?
That is what I said.
When I regain control,
I will access the flux light
stored in the light cube cluster.
Then I will delete every resident of
the realms of humanity and darkness.
That said,
if you decide to help me, and
I eliminate Administrator,
I will have full access
to all of my authority.
Then, before I extinguish this
world, I can grant you one wish.
To a certain degree, anyway.
If you single out those
you would like to save,
I will refrain from
deleting their floodlights.
Instead, I will archive them.
After you escape to the real world,
you can save their light cubes.
I should be able to set aside ten or so.
I got a pick.
Wait a sec.
Something doesn't add up here.
You said your soul's a copy of hers.
That means you got the selfish
part of the nobility in you, too.
The drive to put your wants and
needs above everyone else's.
So why'd you wait here all by yourself?
And for two hundred years?
You could have found a place far away from
Administrator and had some kind of life.
The Cardinal's sub-process
was burned into me.
That means my core desires
amount to only one thing.
To eliminate Administrator and
restore normal function here.
To me,
there is no way to have a
properly functioning world unless
the corrupting element is dealt
with and the slate wiped clean.
Actually, on second thought...
Perhaps you're right.
I do harbor one desire.
Something I was desperate to experience
just once for the last two hundred years.
Kirito, would you stand up, please?
This should do.
Alright, please step forward.
Come closer. Why?
Don't argue with me.
Raise your arms, please. Like this?
In front of you, and
make a circle with them.
Honestly, how dense are you?
So this is it.
Now I see.
This is what it means to be human.
To be held.
It's so warm and comforting.
After 200 years, this
makes the wait worth it.
To think something so simple
could be so satisfying.
The wait was more than worth it.
Well, how long are you planning
to stand there like that?
Sorry, just being human.
So then, what's your decision?
Will you help me stop
Administrator, or not?
Yeah, okay.
I'll help you with this plan of yours.
Sort of.
Look, I get where you're
coming from and all.
But I'm not gonna give up on this world!
And I won't give up on its people!
I'll help you, but I'll still
try and find a way to save them.
Honestly, your optimism is absurd?
Maybe so.
But if everything gets deleted, so do you.
If I can't figure this out,
You can bet you'll be one of the
ten people I'm gonna want saved.
Could you be any more foolish?
How do you expect me to extinguish
this world if I am not present?
To perform the task, don't know.
Hey, I'll do whatever you say,
but I'm gonna try to come up With
a better solution, all the same.
Someday you too will know the
bitterness of resignation.
It is not the same as trying and Failing.
It is being forced to admit failure
regardless of how hard you try.
There you are.
We thought you were still in the bath.
I'm sorry, I guess I lost track of time.
So uh, cardinal and I were talking.
She used to be the the pontifex
here till administrator.
kicked her out and took over her job.
You're a Pontifex?
Don't worry, she's on our side.
She's gonna help us fight
the Integrity Knights.
You will? Yeah,
she wants to get her
title as Pontifex back,
but to do that, she's gonna have
to take down Administrator first.
So, like, she sorta
suggested we join forces.
Mm-hmm.
There's this girl, an Integrity
Knight called Alice Synthesis 30.
I think she's the same person as an Alice.
Zoo bird from rule it do you know if
she is i'm sorry but the information
i'm able to access here is extremely
limited i know integrity knight
alice was born but no other details
however i can tell you how to undo
the synthesis ritual the sacred art
that creates integrity knights and how
do i do that simply remove the piety
module all the knights have one in
their forehead it looks like a
triangular prism we saw one once the piety
module is inserted it effectively
blocks the links to memories with
that the prospective knight's past is
sealed away the result a knight who
is loyal to the church and to their
creator the pontifex we almost broke
the spell on one of them we reminded
him of who he used to be and the
crystal popped out that is not enough
to free a knight another element is
required in order to break the spell
and what would that be the thing that
once existed in the place where
the module was inserted or more
specifically a memory fragment when
the integrity knight treasures the most
administrator is a cautious woman i
don't doubt she keeps all the memory
fragments close at hand if anywhere
they'd be in her chamber located on the
top floor of the central cathedral.
Okay, so, to turn the knights
back to the way they were,
we need to get our hands
on their memory fragments.
But I doubt the Integrity Knights are just
going to let us walk up
to Administrator's room.
I bet we're going to have to fight every
one of them all the way to
the top of the cathedral.
Don't be naive.
An Integrity Knight does not stop
until either you or they are dead.
I can help you get
equipment that is equal to
theirs, but that is all
the assistance I can offer.
The rest will be up to your skills and
whether you have the stamina to endure.
If Alice shows up and I have to fight her,
I don't want to hurt her.
I can't.
I just want to take her
back to our village.
I know.
I understand.
Your intention is honorable, and I
have an idea that should satisfy you.
So don't fret.
When you come across Alice the Knight,
you'll be armed with
something that won't kill her.
I made them special.
Daggers?
Obviously.
Whoever they pierce will
be instantly linked to
me in this library by an
unbreakable connection.
The person will then be susceptible
to whatever sacred art I cast.
Take them.
All you have to do is pierce her
flesh with just one of those daggers.
In that instant, I will use my sacred
arts to put her into a deep sleep.
She will stay that way
until you have her memory
fragment and are ready
to remove the synthesis.
All right, then.
If I can't manage to talk sense
into her, I will use your daggers.
Actually, one of those is
intended for administrator.
The other one is supposed to be a spare.
Either way, who gets stabbed
with which is up to you now.
Damn, talk about putting on the pressure.
Wait, we still need gear.
You said you'd help us get stuff
that's equal to what the knights have.
You and Eugeo have powerful
swords of your own, do you not?
Those should be more than
equal to what any knight has.
Does that mean what I think it does?
Can you get our swords back? Of course.
There is an armory on the
third floor of the cathedral.
That is most likely where
they are being kept.
By the way, how far up do we have to
go to get to Administrator's room?
Each year, the central cathedral
grows taller than the last.
So, her chamber should be on
the hundredth floor by now.
Unfortunately, there is one
more thing you need to do.
You don't say.
Your swords are powerful,
that much is true.
But they're not enough to bring
down the Integrity Knights.
They know a technique.
Which allows them to
amplify their weapons'
abilities many times over
what is normal. Right.
I believe it's called
Perfect Weapon Control.
Once they activate the spell,
Divine Weapons take on the properties
of the thing the weapon once was.
In other words, Perfect Control
releases the weapon's memory.
As a result, it can unleash potent
attacks that are far beyond normal.
I will arm you both with that power.
Close your eyes and think of your sword.
All right, it is done.
Here, commit all the words to memory.
Now then, Eugeo and Kirito, the
fate of this world is up to you.
Whether it is engulfed in
hellfire or vanishes entirely?
Or with any luck, perhaps
you'll find a third path!
Regardless, I have told
you all that I can tell.
And given you all that I can give.
All that is left is to
trust in yourselves.
Thank you for all your help, Cardinal!
I know I'll make it to
the top of the cathedral.
And restore Alice's memory.
Oh, no, Ben. Off with you.
If I could heal that hurt a little bit,
I'd better be able to heal
that hurt a little bit.
Realist to you!